Register of the Jan Karski Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Audio-Visual File, circa 1938-2007. (Box 25-35)
  - Audio cassette tapes, 1986-1997; 87 tapes (Box 25-29)
    - Sound recording of Page One show 470, 1990 (Box 28)
      A news magazine-style program with a segment detailing the work of Jan Karski in the Polish Underground. In addition to Karski recalling his memories, a narractor/anchor comments and provides context. Among the people Karski speaks about meeting are Anthony Eden, Lord Cranston, H. G. Wells, and Franklin D. Roosevelt. The other segment is about the film The Nasty Girl. The movie concerns a girl exploring the impact of the holocaust in her hometown, only to find her community unsupportive of her effort. In English. Cassette 47.28. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003355
    - Voice of America broadcast recording, 1995 April 13 (Box 28)
      Includes an interview with Jan Karski. Cassette 48.29. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003356
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation RadioWorks Interview of Jan Karski, 1995 April 27 (Box 28)
      In English. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003357
    - Polskie Radio sound recording, 1995 May 14 (Box 28)
      Elize Boja (?) interviews Jan Karski. In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003358
    - BBC Polish Service sound recording, 1995 January 26 (Box 28)
      In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003359
    - Monitor Radio broadcast sound recording, 1993 April (Box 28)
      Near the 50th anniversary, this Christian Science Monitor broadcast remembers the Warsaw Uprising in the Warsaw Ghetto. In English. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003360
    - Sound recording of a program concerning the work of Jan Karski, 1997 October 24 (Box 28)
      "Der Kurier aus dew Ghetto," Jan Karski - Eiu Portrat. In German. Cassette 54.35. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003361
    - Sound recordings, 1997 June 20 - July 2 (Box 28)
      In German. Side A: Jan Karski, WDR 3 (Koln), Sendung v. 2.7.97, "Aw Abeud vorgestellt", 22.30-23.00 uhr, Journalistin: Cornelia Beuel Koln. Side B: Jan Karski: SWF/S2 Kultur sendung: "Buchzeit" 20.6.97 14.30-1500 Redaction Panel Assall Bespreduing: Stefan Berkholz, Berlin. In German. Cassette 55.36. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003363
    - Sound recording, 1996 June 28 (Box 28)
      Radio (?) program featuring Jan Karski. In Polish. Cassette 56.37. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003364
    - Voice of America interview with Jan Karski, undated (Box 28)
      In Polish. Label reads: Voice of America interview - Maciej Wishgriski, I. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003365
    - Sound recording of an interview with Jan Karski for Voice of America, undated (Box 29)
      In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003522
    - Sound recording of an interview with Jan Karski for Voice of America, 1994 January 12 - December 1 (Box 29)
      In Polish. Label reads: Polish: Top Ten SRC: 12/01/94 For: Polish/Zorniak. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003523
    - Voice of America broadcast recordings featuring Jan Karski, 1996 September (Box 29)
      This extended interview, in 31 parts (part 18 mentions the Hoover Institution) spans 13 audio cassettes. While most of the audio consists of interviews with Karski in Polish, there are some extraneous, other VOA programs on the tapes, including English lessons. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003527
    - The Radio Foundation broadcast recording: Bridges, 1994-1996 (Box 29)
      Bridges: a Liberal/Conservative Dialogue with Larry Josephson, devotes a show to its guest Jan Karski and Karski's biographer, Tom Wood. Topics include why he sympathized with the Poles, his work with the Polish Underground, the level of Karski's commitment to the movement, and interacting with British and American officials. The theme music used in the show are arrangements of a J. S. Bach organ fugue. In English. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003873
    - WPLN Tennessee Public Radio broadcast recording: Consider This, 1996 April 29 (Box 29)
      Jan Karski and E. Thomas Wood reflect on Karski's work during WWII. Among the topics covered are the state of the Polish ghetto under Nazi occupation and Karski's meeting with President Roosevelt. In English. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003874
    - As It Happens radio broadcast recording, undated (Box 29)
      Among the segments is an interview with Jan Karski recalling the Nazi death camps and Final Solution. In English. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003876
    - Sound recording of a Warsaw roundtable discussion, 1993 July (Box 29)
      This is a recording of a roundtable discussion at a conference convened by Jan Karski. It concerns anti-Semitism and the roles various institutions (media, church, etc.) play in it. In Polish and English. Use copy reference number: 46033_a_0003877
  - Video (DVD)
    - Unveiling of a Monument to Jan Karski, 2007 (Folder 30: 1)
  - Video (VHS videocassettes), 1987-2007
    - General
      - America and the Holocaust - Deceit and Indifference, 1994; 2 copies (Folder 30: 2-3)
      - American Jewish Committee Concert Silenced Voices, 1995 (Folder 30: 4)
      - Escape from Sobibor, 1987 (Folder 30: 5)
      - Holocaust Memorial Cantata, undated (Folder 30: 6)
      - Holocaust Memorial Soil Dedication Ceremony, undated (Folder 30: 7)
      - The Other Side of Faith, undated (Folder 30: 8)
      - Poland, undated (Folder 30: 9)
      - BBC2 documentary video: The Pope, the Jews and the Nazis, 1995; (2 copies) (Folder 30: 10-11)
        This is a documentary video about Pope Pius XII's actions during WWII. It includes an interview with Jan Karski. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003557
      - The Prophets of the Modern State of Israel, undated (Folder 30: 12)
      - Siostra Jana - Prawdziwy Sługa Boży, 2000 (Folder 30: 13)
      - A Time to Gather Stones Together, 1993; (copy 1) (Folder 30: 14)
      - A Time to Gather Stones Together, 1993; (copy 2) (Folder 31: 1)
      - Weapons of Spirit, 1989 (Folder 31: 2)
      - Without Pity and Mercy, undated (Folder 31: 3)
      - Zegota - Council for Aid to Jews in Occupied Poland, 1998 (Folder 31: 4)
      - Sy Rotter documentary video: Zegota: a Time to Remember, 1992 (Folder 31: 5)
        Produced by Sy Rotter and Andrzej Sikora, this video includes an interview with Jan Karski. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003558
    - Lectures, interviews, and public events with Karski's participation
      - Auschwitz Ceremony, 1995 (Folder 31: 6)
      - Jan Karski interview on the Bob Lewandowski Show, 1987 (Folder 31: 7)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003563
      - Jan Karski interview on CNN international news feature, 1995; Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003564 (Folder 31: 8)
      - Dyskusja z Giedroyciem. Wizyta w Łodzi, undated (Folder 31: 9)
      - Jan Karski interview on the Diane Glazer Show, 1995; Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003565 (Folder 31: 10)
      - Excerpts from Dinner Presentation: Dr. Jan Karski Recipient of the 1991 H.M.C. Righteousness Award (Folder 31: 11)
      - Godzina Szczerości - Jan Karski, undated; 2 copies (Folder 31: 12-13)
      - Godzina Szczerości - Jan Karski, undated; 2 copies (Folder 32: 1-2)
      - Holocaust Memorial Center - Fall Lectures Series, 1987-1988 (Folder 32: 3)
      - Holocaust Memorial Center private interview with Jan Karski, 1987; Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003567 (Folder 32: 4)
      - Interview with Wladyslaw Zbik, undated (Folder 32: 5)
      - Jan Karski - Georgetown University, 1990 (Folder 32: 6)
      - Jan Karski - Holocaust Center, 1993 (Folder 32: 7)
      - Jan Karski interview on World News Now, 1997; Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003568 (Folder 32: 8)
      - Jan Karski - Wywiad, 1993 (Folder 32: 9)
      - Lecture - King's College, 1995 (Folder 32: 10)
      - Memorial Concert Shalom in Krakow, 1993 (Folder 32: 11)
      - Muzeum Lubelskie, 1998 (Folder 32: 12)
      - National Civic Commemoration of the Days of Remembrance, 1991 (Folder 32: 13)
      - Passing Through, 1990 (Folder 33: 1)
      - Presentation of Karski at Jewish Book Festival of Greater Washington D.C. by Jan Karski and Thomas Wood, 1994 (Folder 33: 2)
      - Professor Jan Karski at UCLA, 1995 (Folder 33: 3)
      - Professor Jan Karski interview - Wywiad, circa 1993 (Folder 33: 4)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003569
      - World War II Allied Secret Diplomacy Toward Poland. Jan Karski U.M. - Flint, 1990 (Folder 33: 5)
      - Wywiad z "Salusiem". Professor Salomon Fo, Krynica, undated (Folder 33: 6)
    - Videos about Karski, with and without his participation
      - Doktorat Honoris Causa UMCS w Lublinie, 1995; 2 copies (Folder 33: 7-8)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003570
      - Polish Television Studio 3 video: Holocaust Memorial Museum with Professor Jan Karski, 1999 (Folder 33: 9)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003578
      - Neue Zurcher Zeitung documentary: Holocaust - Nachrichten aus dem Untergrund, undated (Folder 33: 10)
        In German. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003579
      - Jan Karski - Hero, 1999 (Folder 33: 11)
      - Catholic Telecommunications Network of America video: Jews Honor a Polish Catholic, 1994; Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003580 (Folder 33: 12)
      - Kulturzeit: Jan Karski, undated (Folder 33: 13)
        In German. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003581
      - Kuroń i Moja Historia, Warszawa, undated (Folder 34: 1)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003582
      - PBS documentary: Messenger from Poland, undated (Folder 34: 2)
        From the PBS television series The Struggles for Poland. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003584
      - Telewizja Poland documentary: Moja Misja, 1997; 3 copies (Folder 34: 3-5)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003585
      - My Mission, 1996; 2 copies (Folder 34: 6-7)
      - Australian Broadcast Corporation television show: Lateline with Fiona Clark: The Myth of Rescue, 1997; Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003587 (Folder 34: 8)
      - They Risked Their Lives. Rescuers of the Holocaust, undated (Folder 34: 9)
      - Documentary: Swoi czy obcy, undated (Folder 34: 10)
        In Polish. Use copy reference number: 46033_v_0003588
      - Popsuta tajima, undated (Folder 34: 11)
      - Kazimierz Dolny, undated (Folder 34: 12)
      - Jewish Journal - Professor Karski, 1988 (Folder 35: 1)
- Photographs, 1939-1945. (Envelope 46033 A-X)
  Prints depicting events, places and people related to Poland during World War II. See also box 1 and box 25
  - 25 prints depicting scenes in Poland during the German occupation, 1939-1945 (Envelope 46033 A)
  - 42 prints depicting Warsaw during the Warsaw Uprising, 1943-1944 (Envelope 46033 B)
  - 240 prints depicting scenes in Poland during the German occupation with emphasis on Nazi propaganda and the treatment of the Jews (Envelope 46033 C-F)
  - 130 prints depicting the Polish Underground Army and its operations during the German occupation (Envelope 46033 G-H)
  - 14 prints depicting the Warsaw Uprising, 1944 (Envelope 46033 I)
  - 131 prints depicting Polish participation in World War II outside of Poland (Envelope 46033 J-O)
  - 23 prints depicting Polish women in the Armed Forces outside of Poland during World War II (Envelope 46033 P)
  - 35 prints depicting the Polish Army in the USSR, 1941-1942, and Polish deportees in the USSR (Envelope 46033 Q)
  - 34 prints depicting Polish refugees in foreign countries (Envelope 46033 R)
  - 37 prints depicting scenes at the site of the Katyń Forest Massacre and documents of the investigation (Envelope 46033 S)
  - 20 prints depicting Polish children in emigration (Envelope 46033 T)
  - 80 prints depicting General Sikorski's funeral, 1943 (Envelope 46033 U)
  - 30 prints depicting scenes in Poland during World War II and texts of documents descriptive of conditions at that time (Envelope 46033 V)
  - 58 prints depicting Polish Air Force and Navy personnel, 1942 (Envelope 46033 W)
  - 39 prints depicting the Polish Armed Forces during World War II. (Envelope 46033 X)
    Includes prints depicting General Sikorski as well as Polish diplomats and statesmen of that period
- Microfilm Reels, 1940-1944; 26 reels
  Microfilm copies of Polish underground publications under German occupation
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1940 (Reel 1)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1941 (Reel 2-7)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1941-1942 (Reel 8)
  - Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1943 (Reel 9)
  - Walka, 1943-1944 (Reel 10-11)
  - Przez Walkę do Zwycięstwa, 1943 (Reel 11)
  - Pobódka, 1940-1942 (Reel 12)
  - Polska Ludowa, 1943 (Reel 13)
  - Gwardia Ludowa, 1943 (Reel 13)
  - Dzwon Polski, 1943 (Reel 13)
  - Żywią, 1943 (Reel 14)
  - Wolność Robotnicza, 1944 (Reel 14)
  - Demokrata, 1944 (Reel 15)
  - Placówka, 1942 (Reel 15)
  - Polska Walczy (Reel 15)
  - Nowe Drogi, 1943 (Reel 16)
  - Walka Młodych, 1944 (Reel 16)
  - Do Broni, 1943 (Reel 16)
  - Przełom, 1944 (Reel 17)
  - Przegląd Polityczny, 1944 (Reel 17)
  - Polak, 1943 (Reel 17)
  - Głos Warszawy, 1944 (Reel 18)
  - Jutro PN, 1943 (Reel 18)
  - Czyn, 1944 (Reel 18)
  - Zryw, 1943 (Reel 18)
  - Głos Ludu, 1943 (Reel 19)
  - Narod i Wojsko, 1942 (Reel 20)
  - Na Zachodnim Szańcu, 1942-1943 (Reel 21)
  - Szaniec, 1943 (Reel 22)
  - Robotnik, 1944 (Reel 23)
  - Miscellaneous Polish underground publications (Reel 24-26)